Citizen Action of New York; Records apap341
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Citizen Action of New York Records
1983-2008
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap341
11.1 cubic ft.
This collection contains the records Citizen Action of New York. Citizen Action of New York is a grassroots membership organization that fights for social, racial, economic, and enviornmental justice. Working closely with New York State politicans, community organizers, and activists, Citizen Action members hope to end the oppression of marginalized groups.
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted except for some folders related to the hiring of staff and donors to political campaigns. Series 2 also contains two folders that are closed until 2052-2053 due to attorney-client privilege.
Acquisition Information
All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Historical Note
Citizen Action of New York is a grassroots membership organization with chapters and affiliates in major cities across the state. The organization tackles transformative issues affecting society such as affordable healthcare, quality education, public financing of election campaigns, dismantling racism, and a more progressive tax system. To achieve its vision, members fight for social, racial, economic and environmental justice.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains correspondence, administrative files, newspaper articles, press releases, subject files, and legislative materials.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is arranged alphabetically.
Public Advocate; Albany (N.Y.); New York (State); Health care reform; Lobbying--New York (State); Lobbying--Law and legislation; New York (State)--Politics and government.; United States -- Politics and government.
- Administrative Files, 1983-2008; 3 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  - 3 Faces of Power, 2003; 2005 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 8th Annual Leadership Conference, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 15th Anniversary Celebration-Awards Ceremony, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1989 Organizing Plan (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 2000 Goals, Accomplishments, and Unfinished Business (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 2001-Gala (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 2002 Combined Cash Flow USAction/USAEF (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Must consult an archivist before viewing.
  - 2002 Gala (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 2002 USAction Affiliate Electoral Activity Report (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 2003 Gala and 20th Anniversary Celebrating 20 Year of Action for Justice (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 2006 Annual Leadership Conference (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 2007 Leadership Summit (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - A Response to No Fault Medical Negligence Proposals, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - A Taste of Democracy, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - A Taste of Democracy-Donors and Contributors, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Agreement-William McNary, President USAction and Delores Travis, Assistant to the President, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - American Health Security Act vs. The Clinton Proposal, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Annual Work plan: Organizational Goals, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Background Notes: Citizen Action's Organizational and Canvass History, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Being A Great Public Speaker, Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Bi-Weekly Report Form, 2001; Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Board Meeting Minutes (1 of 3), 1989-1991; 1993-1996; 1999-2004 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Board Meeting Minutes (2 of 3), 1989-1991; 1993-1996; 1999-2004 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Board Meeting Minutes (3 of 3), 1989-1991; 1993-1996; 1999-2004 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Brochures, Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Building Assets to Lift Families out of Poverty, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Building Power Through USAction, Undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Bush-"Truth Squad" Draft Proposal, Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - By-Laws For Citizen Action of New York, 1991; Undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - By-Laws of The New York City Regional Board of Citizen Action of New York, Undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Bylaws of USAction, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Campaign Contracts, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Campaign Finance Reform and the 1986 New York State Senate Elections: A Study of the Impact of Proposed Public Financing Legislation on Campaign Spending for Election to the New York State Senate, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Campaign for Health Security, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Campaign for Health Security: Organizers Kit, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Campaign for a Responsible Congress: Focus Group Findings, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Campaign Media and Message Training, Undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Campaign Scrutiny, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Child Health Plus Outreach Project, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Child Health Plus Program-New York State Department of Health Correspondence, 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Citizen Action In the News, 1983; 1986-1988; 1990; 1992; 1999 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Citizen Action Leadership Line, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Citizen Action Management Review Committee, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Citizen Action-National Board Members and Executive Directors, 1984; 1990 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Citizen Action of New York-17 Years of Accomplishments, 1983-2000 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Citizen Action of New York vs. Michael R. Bloomberg, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Citizen Action Updates, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - The Civil Jury System: Accountability, Deterrence, and Fairness, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Clean Election for New York: A Conference on Full Public Financing of Election, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Clean Money, Clean Election-Speakers Training, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Committee for the Future, 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Committee for the Future-1999 Funders (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Community Health Access Project (CHAP), 1995-1997 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Countdown to National HealthCare, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Final Report of Citizen Action for Mark Green, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Financial Records, 1989; 1999-2003 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Fueling New York's Incumbency Machine: Campaign Contributions to the New York State Legislature in 1990, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Gaia Donors, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Goals and Objectives, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Half a Million and One Broken Promises, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Health Care Campaign Annual Meeting, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - The Health Care Crisis in New York: Building a Consumer/Worker Agenda for 1996, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Hegemony in the Post-Industrial Long wave and its Implications for Mass Organizations or What the Hell do we do next? (A Summary of Discussion Held By Staff of Citizen Action of New York), 1985 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - How Likely Leadership Bills are to Meet Citizen Action's Key Principles, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - The Impossible Dream: Tax Credit are a 10-Foot Rope for Uninsured New Yorkers in 40-Foot Hole, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Key Provisions of Committee Health Care Bills, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Leadership Conferences, 2000-2002; Undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Leadership Pledge Program, Undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Legislative Candidate Questionnaires, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Membership Committee, 2000-2003 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Memorandum of Agreement Between USAction and Citizen Action of New York, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Minnesota Refund System, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - National Health Care: An American Priority, 1983-1993 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Native American/Alaskan Native Action Council Position Paper to US Action, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - New York City Chapter Organizing Committee: Electoral Endorsements Subcommittee Meeting, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - New York City Chapter Organizing Committee Meeting Minutes, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - New York State Community of Churches Pamphlets, 1996-1999; Undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - New York State Nurses Association, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - New York State Senate Database Project, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - People of Color Action Council Summit 2001 Report (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Physician Diversity New Strategies Project, 2002-2004 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - The Policy and Political Imperative for Universal Health Care: A White Paper, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Power Toolkit for Local Organizing, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - PPEF and Citizen Action Issues Campaigns, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Premiums Without Benefits, 1990 The Decade-Long Growth in Commercial Health Insurance Industry Waste and Inefficiency, 1990-1993 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - President Bill Clintons Health Care Plan-Slides, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Program Resolution for 2003-2004, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Progressive Leader Awards Reception, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - The Progressive Opening: A Time for Action-Heather Booth. President of Citizen Action, Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Proposal Structure of New National Organization, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Public Financing of Election Campaigns, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - The Public Policy and Education Fund of New York: New York Health Fiscal Analysis of a Public Health Insurance Plan, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Public Policy Education Fund: Voter Registration Project, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Real Campaign Reform? An Analysis of George Pataki, H. Carl McCall and Tom Golisano's Campaign Reform Proposals, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Recommendations for Health Care Reform in New York State As Part of NYHPRM V From the New York State Health Care Campaign, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Recommendations for Managing the Work of the President, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Remarks of Bruce Popper for WXXI-AM Radio Re-National Health Care Reform, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Report on USAction Affiliate Capacity, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Reports, 1987-1988; 1992-1998; 2001 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Resolution for the Continuation of the Culture, Process, and Accountability Committee, Undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Resolution of the Board of Directors of USAction, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Risk Adjustment and Federal Health Care Reform: Report Prepared for Gay Men's Health Crisis, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Single Payer National Health Insurance Briefing Book, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Staff Evaluations, 2000-2001 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Staff Salaries, 2002; Undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Steve Max: A Real Economic Future for our Children, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Steve Max-The Danger to the Democrats of Conventional Wisdom, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Steve Max-Working for Nothing Will Save Your Job! But There Is a Better Way, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Strategic Planning Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Summary of Retirement Security Campaigns in CT, IA, MN, NJ, and PA, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Supervision Styles to Match Staff Needs, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Tax Campaign Organizing Activities, 1989-1991 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - USAction 2002 Director Review/Staff and Board Survey Responses (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - USAction-Board Members, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - USAction Capacity Program, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - USAction Delegates Assembly-Jeff Blum, Executive Director, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - USAction Draft Resolution on War with Iraq, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - USAction Education Fund-2004 Civic Engagement Program, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - USAction Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1999-2001 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - USAction Executive Director, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - USAction: Five Year Strategic Goals, 2003-2008 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - USAction Flyer, Undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - USAction Grassroots Political Program, 2001-2002 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - USAction Major Donor Program, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - USAction Political Committee Recommendations to Executive Committee, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - USAction Strategy Plan-Proposal for How it is Reviewed and Adopted by Affiliate and Regionals, Undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - USAction and USAction Education Fund February Strategy Meeting Information, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - What Should National Staff Do?, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - What is USAction??, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Winning Progressive Change: A USAction Plan for 2003-2004 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Wisconsin Citizen Action-1999 Annual Report (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - W.K. Kellogg Foundation, 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Who Plays the Lottery: Demographic Characteristics of Lottery Players in the U.S./Revenue for Political Campaign Financing in New York State: A New Lottery Game, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Volunteer 2004 Contribution (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Volunteer 2004 Training Manual and Organizer Materials (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Your Right to Specialist Care: A Survey of HMOs in New York, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Zogby International Poll Results, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 55)
- Legislation, 1985-2006; 7.8 cubic ft.
  Scope and Contents
  This series is related to Citizen Action's involvement in social, racial, economic, and enviornmental justice. The first sub-series, lobbying, includes records relating to Citizen Action's advoacy and action. The second sub-series, subject files, includes records that supported Citizen Action's mission, but were produced by other organizations and individuals. This series does contain restrictions. Please consult an archivist before using the collection.
  - Lobbying, 1986-2006; 5.9 cubic ft.
    This sub-series is arranged alphabetically.
    This sub-series includes records related to Citzen Action's involvement in political, racial, social, and economic issues. Many of these issues were related to clean money campaigns and health care. The sub-series includes pamphlets, flyers, letters to Congressmen, news releases, and VHS tapes. The VHS tapes include video footage of members of Citizen Action lobbying, speeches from politicans at their galas and meetings, and other programs that the organization hosted. Some folders in this sub-series are restricted, so please consult an archivist before use. Two folders are closed due to attorney client privlige.
    - 1996 Pataki Budget: What It Means for Education, Higher Education, Welfare and Health Care, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1997 New York City Mayoral Campaign-Campaign Funding Report Through April 1997 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 2000 Campaign Finance Reform, 1997-2000 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 2000 Children's Defense Fund Action Council Nonpartisan Congressional Voting Record, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 800,001 Broken Promises: New Yorkers Waiting for Health Insurance Promised More Than Three Years Ago, 1999; 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - A Campaign for New York City's Parks, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - AD Campaign To Show How President Bush Avoids Paying State Taxes, 1990; 1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Ad Hoc Task Force on New York's Prospective Hospital Reimbursement Methodology, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Aetna U.S. Healthcare (AUSHC), 1999 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Affordable Medicare Prescription Drug Benefit, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - American Health Security Act-Congress' Response, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - American Health Security Act Highlights and Summaries, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Andrew Cuomo Campaign Finance Reform, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Asbestos: Letters to Congressmen, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Bell Atlantic, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Best Practices Member Handbook, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Bringing Campaign Finance Reform to Albany: A Call for Statewide Action, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Broken Promises, Broken Hearts: New Yorkers Still Waiting for Health Insurance Governor and Legislature Promised Two Years Ago, 2002; 2004 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Bust the Ghosts: Close Corporate Tax Loopholes, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Campaign for Health Security, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Campaign for Healthy Children Outreach Project, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Campaign Reform, 1998-1999; 2004 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Campaign Spending Study, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Capital Bargains, Capital Gains, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Child Health Plus Outreach Project: Response to Request for Proposals to Conduct Community Outreach for the Child Health Plus Program, 1995-1997 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Children Will Love Health Insurance At Age 13, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Citizen Action in the News (1 of 2), 1987-1998 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Citizen Action in the News (2 of 2), 1987-1998 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Citizen Action's Endorsements for State Senate, Undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Citizen Action's State Funds for Partisan Political Purposes, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Citizen of Albany for Responsible Education, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Clean Money/Clean Elections (1 of 2), 1997-2002 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Clean Money/Clean Elections (2 of 2), 1997-2002 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Color of Money in New York: Federal Campaign Contributions and Race, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Color of Money: Race and Campaign Funding in State Politics-Illinois, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Comptroller Candidate Interviews, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Consumers' Privacy Concerns, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Consumer Protection Grant Project-Managed Care Bill of Right, 1996-2000 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Consumer Group Endorses Weir, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Corporate Campaign Contributions, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Critical Choices in Health Care Reform, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Empty Pockets, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Enron Accounting, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Equal Protection of the Voting Rights, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Eric Ruben-Schneiderman Against Merit Behavioral Care Corp., Sati Ahluwalia M.D. and Empire Blue Cross and Blue Shield, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Expanding Health Insurance Access in New York State, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Excess Costs and Politics MTA Contracting, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Family Daycare Insurance, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Family Health Plus, 1999-2001 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Federal Budget: What's At Stake for New York, 2003-2005 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Federal Tax Windfall, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Further Resolution on Iraq, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Governor Pataki's Campaign Finance Reform Proposal, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Grassley-Baucus Medicore Prescription Drug Proposal, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Great Life Insurance Rip-Off: The Potential Cost to New York Consumers of Mutual Holding Company Legislation, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Greater New York Hospital Association, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Half-A-Million and one Broken Promises, 1992; 1999-2000; 2004 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Half of All House Votes with Gingrich, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Health Care as Good as Congress: Nothing Less, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Health Care Campaign-Committee Meeting (1 of 3), 1996-2001 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Health Care Campaign-Committee Meeting (2 of 3), 1996-2001 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Health Care Campaign-Committee Meeting (3 of 3), 1996-2001 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Health Care Education Project-Post-Election Polling Survey, 1999-2001 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Health Care for all Ambulance, 1989-1991 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Health Care for All-Rally, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Health Care Reform Act, 1999; 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Health USA Act of 1991-A Proposal to make Health Care Affordable and Available to All Americans, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Hillary Clinton vs. Rick Lazzo, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - HMO Liability, 1996-2000 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Hospital Charity Care, 2002-2006 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Hospital Global Budgeting in New York, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - How A Company lets Its Cash Talk/Schumer Turns Tort Reformer with New Bill, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - How Much Health Care Can New York Families Afford?, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - How to Win New York Health-Candidate Packet, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - How to Win HR-1300 The Universal Health Care Act-Candidate Packet, Undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Independent Review, 1998-2000 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Legislative Candidate Questionnaires, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Limited Liability Corporations and New York and Nursing Homes, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Mainstream Coalition Proposed Agreement, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Managed Care Legislation-HMO, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Managed Care Legislation of 1996 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Managed Competition, 1991-1993 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Material for Health Care Organizing, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - McCall For Governor, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Medical Alert: House Republican Medicare and Medicaid Plans, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Medical Malpractice, 1987; 1991; 1993-1994; 1996-1999; 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Medical Saving Account, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Medicare, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Medicare Assignment and Related Senior Health Issues, 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Mobilizing America to Save our Health Care, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Modern Wrongful Death Law, 1995; 1997 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Money Marathon: Big Bucks and the Race for Governor of New York, 2001-2002 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - MTA Fare Hike, 2002-2003 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - MTBE Ban, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Mutual Holding Company Legislation, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Mutual Holding Companies and the Financial Services Act, 1997-1999 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - National Council of La Raza-Medical Benefits, 2002-2003 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - New York Citizen Committee for Occupational Health-Citizen Action Response to Asbestos, 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - New York Health, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - New York State Assembly Passes Universal Health Care Bill, 1991-1993 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - New York State Board of Elections: Compliance with the States Election Law-H. Carl McCall, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - New York State Health Care Campaign (1 of 4), 1986-1996 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - New York State Health Care Campaign (2 of 4), 1986-1996 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - New York State Health Care Campaign (3 of 4), 1986-1996 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - New York State Health Care Campaign (4 of 4), 1986-1996 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - New York State Senate Proposal, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - New York State Senator Endorsements, 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - New Yorkers Beware, Don't be Fooled By MTBE Producers Trying to Pull the Wool Over Our Eyes, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - NYNEX-Bell Atlantic Merger, 1995-1998 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Patients Bill of Rights, 1997-2000 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Pay to Play: Campaign Contributions to Governor Pataki and Funds from the Empire State Development Corporation, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Policy Holders Across the State, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Poisons in our Neighborhoods: A Survey of Toxic Pollution By New York Manufactures (1 of 2), 1989-1991; 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Poisons in our Neighborhoods: Toxins Pollution in New York (2 of 2), 1989-1991; 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Prescription Drug Prices, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - President Bill Clinton-New Health Care Position, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - ProNet: Prospectively Paid Health Project Newsletter, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Product Liability, 1994-1996; 1998 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Proposed Amendment of Part 52 (Regulation 62) of the Title II, NYCRR, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 10)